You know, you should learn from all of the horrors perpetrated by your children.
America comes out of Europe.
I was born in Harlem.
You have a Harlem here. You have a Brooklyn Bridge here.
And you cannot pretend that what is happening on the other side of the water where you sent your children.
New York was New Amsterdam.
When New York was New Amsterdam.
You are still connected, yes.
Do we see a difference between the United States and Holland?
No. No.
Do we have to live the same history?
I hope you don't.
If I were you, if I were you, I would study, I would take it as an object lesson, and don't do what we did.
You haven't got to build another Harlem just because you did it once.
At all.
I was born in Harlem with one A. You got one up the road with two A's.
You haven't got to do what your children did.
You ought to learn from this example and understand that it is not a romantic matter.
It is the unutterable truth.
All men are brothers.
That's the bottom line.
If you can't take it from there, you can't take it at all.
You have been visiting Holland not for the first time.
You have been here seven years ago.
Oh, many years.
Did Holland and Amsterdam change for you?
I mean, as far as these problems we are talking about.
Everything I told you was going to happen has happened.
As Ray Charles says, I hate to say I told you so.
What did you tell us?
But I told you so.
That you were building another Harlem.
That you were going to do exactly what your heirs in America have done and you're doing it.
At this very moment, you think?
At this very moment.
Where are the facts?
What are you thinking about?
The people in the streets.
You have people in the streets who have never seen the colony in which their fathers were born.
We might be talking about Amsterdam.
If you are not very, if you don't use us as an example, by which I mean the American example.